

Email: hello@jackcrawford.co.nz | Mobile: +64 27 251 7174

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/jackwardcrawford</u>

Portfolio: jackcrawford.co.nz | GitHub: github.com/jack-crawford-1

PROFILE

With over 10 years of account management experience, I developed strong problem-solving skills and a curiosity that drives me to explore challenges in depth. My passion for technology led me to complete Dev Academy's Software Development Bootcamp, where I built a foundation in modern web development.

At Trade Me, I am expanding my expertise by working with Paystation's API and payment integrations, gaining hands-on experience in API development, e-commerce platforms, and technical troubleshooting. I'm deepening my understanding of REST APIs, authentication, and software architecture while strengthening my ability to bridge business needs with technical solutions.

.

SKILLS

Frontend: React, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS **Backend**: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL

Web Services: REST APIs, OAuth2

Version Control & Testing: Git, Vitest, Mocha

Development: Agile methodologies, Project Planning

CURRENT PROJECTS

Hiking App (currently developing)

A web app designed for hikers to share and access trail information. Using data from the DOC and LINZ API's along with geoJson, TilerMaps and a PostgreSQL database.

Built with: React, Typescript, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Tailwind CSS, Axios, Proj4, TilerMaps, GoogleMaps.

Community Garden App

A full-stack Next.js application designed to help community garden organisers and members manage garden plots. It includes features for viewing available plots and adding new plots to the database. with Google Maps integration for plotting garden locations and converting latitude and longitude.

Built with: Next.js, TypeScript, Prisma, SQLite database and Google Maps.

EXPERIENCE

Trade Me Wellington, NZ

Technical Integrations Specialist, Sep 2024 - Present

- Support merchants with Paystation API integration
- Provide technical guidance on API implementations, troubleshooting integration issues.
- Collaborate with product, and engineering teams to enhance e-commerce solutions
- Improve documentation and developer resources for merchants

Account Manager, Oct 2020 - Dec 2023

- Managed advertising and recruitment strategies for high-profile businesses, enhancing client engagement and outcomes.
- Worked with Trade Me Analytics, Product, and Engineering teams on various projects, including collaborating on the integration of the new Trade Me Jobs API with external partners.

Dev Academy Aotearoa Wellington, NZ

Full Stack Developer (Bootcamp), Jan 2024 - May 2024

NZQA Level 6 Certificate in Applied Software Development

- Completed 700+ hours of hands-on coding in JavaScript, TypeScript, React,.
- Built full-stack applications, gaining expertise in frontend, backend, and database development.
- Worked in agile, team-based environments, focusing on collaboration, problemsolving, and rapid iteration

Career Break, Wellington, NZ, Feb 2020 - Sep 2020

Lead Chat; Melbourne, AUS

Account Manager, Nov 2016 - Dec 2019

- Effectively managed clients across multiple time zones including the US and UK.
- Ensured service delivery met client expectations and worked with to optimise leads.
- Met new business targets through successful prospecting, pipeline management, and sales cycle management.

Smudge; Melbourne, AUS

Digital Sales Manager, Jun 2016 - Dec 2016

- Launched display advertising as a new product, expanding revenue streams.
- Partnered with leading Australian brands for integrated digital and print campaigns.
- Worked with SEO specialists to improve site traffic and digital engagement.

Zomato; Melbourne, AUS

Key Accounts Manager, Jan 2015 - Jun 2016

- First sales hire in Australia, exceeding sales targets in a startup environment.
- Recruited, trained, and mentored a high-performing sales team.
- Planned and executed on-site marketing events to boost client visibility.

EDUCATION

NZQA Level 6 Certificate in Applied Software Development, Jan 2024 - May 2024

REFERENCES

Available on request.